Contact

+4915752577230 (Mobile) robert.focke@member.fsf.org

www.linkedin.com/in/robertfocke (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Linux

SQL

Python

Prize

Languages

Afrikaans (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)
German (Professional Working)

Honors-Awards

3rd Place, Mobile Application Development Challenge Information Technology Subject

Robert Focke

Software Developer, Entrepreneur

Johannesburg Area, South Africa

Summary

I am a young professional in the computer science and linguistics field, interested in machine learning, big data and computational linguistics.

I have good knowledge of general software development including full-stack web development and modern devops, with experience working with both corporate and startup clients.

Experience

Clickwash

Co-Founder

October 2018 - Present

Pretoria Area, South Africa

Involved in the following:

System design and full-stack web development.

Python, JS, CSS and HTML.

Geographical clustering.

Open Source Routing Machine (OSRM).

Travelling salesman problem.

Business development.

Marketing.

Self-employed Software Consultant

October 2018 - Present

Johannesburg Area, South Africa

Full stack web development

Custom software development

Machine learning applications

Fridaysuite Pty Ltd.

Co-Founder

October 2018 - Present

Pretoria Area, South Africa

System design and coordination of development of the Fridaysuite web application. Development of software predominantly written in Python (flask) and JavaScript. Automation of deployment to Amazon Web Services using the Boto3 python SDK. Administration of the Fridaysuite system using nginx, gunicorn, supervisord and laminar.

SAP

1 year 9 months

Knowledge Manager (Working Student) January 2018 - September 2018 (9 months) Berlin Area, Germany

Working student position.

Technical enablement, information development and content creation within the topics of Machine Learning, Cloud Computing and Digital Transformation.

Product documentation working closely with development, UX design, agile product management, business development and customers.

Product testing, QA relating to the SAP Leonardo Machine Learning platform.

Software Engineer (Working Student) January 2017 - December 2017 (1 year) Berlin Area, Germany

Working as a working student in the Berlin office of the SAP Innovation Centre Network. Working as part of the team developing the SAP Leonardo ML Platform. Python, Java, C++ and Groovy development in an agile environment.

Worked as part of the Google-SAP partnership, creating a proxy of Google's speech recognition service. Also worked with ABBYY OCR Engine, Docker, CloudFoundry, Flask, Jenkins.

HomeToGo System Administrator (Working Student) February 2016 - July 2016 (6 months) Berlin Area, Germany

Manage network in the Berlin Office (Juniper Switches, Mikrotik Routers, Cisco APs). Resolving IT related problems. Stock-taking of IT related assets.

Page 2 of 3

Raspberry Pis for PR and Google Analytics. Automation using shell scripting (Bash),

Education

Open Source Society University
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2018 - 2020)

Technische Universität Berlin Coursework, Computer Engineering · (2015 - 2018)

Pretoria Boys High School High School · (2010 - 2014)